mines.edu 2019-12-08

# Privacy Statement - Privacy

**Mines’ Privacy Statement**

Colorado School of Mines (“Mines”) is an educational institution located in the United States of America (“USA”). In order to provide you with services and otherwise fulfill our obligations to you, it is necessary for your personal data to be transferred to, and processed in, the USA. Data protection laws differ among  jurisdiction, and the USA may not provide the same level of protection for personal data as your jurisdiction of residence. Mines will take appropriate steps to ensure that your personal data is afforded the same level of protection as described in this Privacy Statement. 

**OUR COMMITMENT TO INDIVIDUAL PRIVACY**  
Mines is committed to ensuring the confidentiality of personal data (defined as any information that can identify a person, directly or indirectly, by an identifier) provided to us by our employees, students or visitors. Mines does maintain reasonable security procedures and practices to maintain privacy and security within the university’s operations.

**INFORMATION COLLECTED**  
Mines collects information from individuals or entities when they access the Mines website. Information that is collected from this contact includes the visitor’s IP address, date and time of website access, webpage(s) visited, and time spent on a webpage. In addition, Mines may also collect any information it receives from your web browser, device, and operating system. This information helps Mines understand aggregate uses of Mines’ site, track usage trends, and improve Mines’ services. It is Mines’ policy to collect the least amount of personal data necessary to fulfill the university’s mission, provide its services, and meet any required legal obligations. This policy applies to the collection of all personal data, cookie, log, and device data, regardless of the source or medium. 

**ACCURACY OF PERSONAL DATA**  
Mines makes reasonable efforts to ensure that the personal data retained about individuals is accurate. Every faculty member, staff member and student has the ability to check and update certain personal data such as his or her address, phone number, etc. online within Trailhead (Self Service > Personal Information).  

For Mines students, questions and requests can be directed to the Registrar’s Office at registrar@mines.edu. For Mines employees, questions and requests can be directed in person to the **[Office of Human Resources](https://www.mines.edu/human-resources/)**. 

**SECURITY**  
The **[security](https://www.mines.edu/ccit/security/)** of your personal data is important to Mines. We have adopted generally accepted industry standards in connection with our data collection, storage, and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure, or destruction of your personal data, and other data stored on Mines’ websites and servers. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commonly acceptable means to protect your personal data, Mines cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

**CHILDREN**  
Mines does not direct services to, and does not knowingly collect or solicit personal data directly from children under the age of 13. Some Mines’ webpages present information about activities that are specifically designed for children. However, these webpages are intended to be used only by adults to voluntarily share information online, so that a child who is under the age of 13 can participate in these activities (e.g., summer camps, classes, programs) or so that the adult and/or child can receive information mailed or emailed from Mines (newsletters, class schedules, recruitment information). When a parent or legal guardian voluntarily signs their child up for one of these programs, the parent or legal guardian may be asked to provide:

  * The child’s full name
  * Full home mailing address
  * Phone number
  * Birth date
  * School, current grade level
  * Email address
  * Parent or legal guardian’s name and email address

The parent or legal guardian supplying the child’s information will be asked to acknowledge that they are, in fact, the parent or guardian who is legally authorized to disclose this information about the child. Any information provided by a parent or legal guardian about their child will not be transferred, disclosed or shared with a third party and will not be used for other purposes.

Parents or legal guardians have the right:

  * To review personal data that has been recorded by a Mines website about their child,
  * To refuse to allow further collection of information about their child,
  * To be given the choice of consenting to the collection and internal use of their child’s personal data, and
  * To require the deletion of any of their child’s personal data that has been recorded. 

See Mines’ Policy on the Protection of Minors [**here**](http://inside.mines.edu/UserFiles/File/PoGo/Policies/HRS/HRS_Policy_Protection_of_Minors.pdf).

DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL DATA TO THIRD PARTIES  
We do not rent or sell your personal data to third parties, but Mines may disclose your personal data to third parties it only in the following ways:

  * With respect to data that constitutes student “education records,” all disclosures are made in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (“FERPA”) and **[Mines’ FERPA Policy](https://3a2vzv37nkuw3esf6a3u2t7s-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/policy-library/wp-content/uploads/sites/87/2018/07/FERPA-Policy-updated-7.30.pdf)**.
  * To our third party service providers and vendors in order to provide products and services on Mines’ behalf. We ask our service providers and vendors to limit their use of personal data, and generally require that they protect your personal data under written agreements;
  * As required or permitted by applicable law, if we believe that such disclosure is (a) reasonably necessary to comply with legal process and law enforcement instructions and orders, such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, judicial proceeding, valid requests for university records under the Colorado Open Records Act; and or other legal process served on us, (b) helpful to prevent, investigate, or identify possible wrongdoing in connection with our Services, (c) helpful to protect our rights, reputation, property, or that of our students, visitors, users, corporate affiliates, or the public, (d) in an emergency, to protect Mines and the safety of our students, faculty, and staff or any third party, or (e) to enforce compliance with our agreements and policies with you; and
  * As otherwise authorized by you.

**PERSONAL DATA OBTAINED FROM THIRD  ** **PARTIES**  
Mines may obtain certain personal data about you from third party sources, which may be used for the purposes and in the ways for which it was collected. In some cases, we may obtain your consent for additional uses. 

**Service Providers** : We use service providers, such as application facilitators (for example, the Common Application and the College Board) and payment processors and analytics providers, to perform services on our behalf. Some of these service providers have access to personal data about you that we may not otherwise have (for example, when you sign up directly with that provider) and may share some or all these data with us. 

**Single Sign-On** : Some of our online services or research activities may allow you to register and login to those services through a third-party platform. When you login to our service through a third-party platform, you allow us to access and collect any personal data from your third-party platform account permitted under the settings and privacy statement of that platform. 

**Supplemental Personal Data** : We may receive additional personal data from third-party sources, such as public or private databases (for example, compilations of email or postal addresses), or companies or institutions that may sponsor or facilitate your participation in one of our programs, which we may also append to existing personal data. 

Mines may obtain other non-personal usage information directly through its webpages or from third party services, such as Google Analytics. This information may include number of visitors to Mines’ website, IP address, technical information about your device or operating system, browser information, time spent on a particular page, etc. 

**THIRD PARTY PRIVACY STATEMENTS**  
Mines relies on third party websites and applications to deliver some of its services. You may be subject to the terms of those third parties, and those terms may differ than those found in Mines’ Privacy Statement. It is your responsibility to review any third party privacy statements and contact the applicable third party if you have questions or requests specific to their privacy statement. 

**RETENTION**  
We will retain your personal data for so long as is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected, or as otherwise required or permitted by law. The erasure of your information shall be subject to the retention periods of applicable federal and state laws and regulations. Certain information, including but not limited to official transcript information, enrollment and commencement records, student financial aid records, and student discipline records will be permanently retained by Mines. 

**COOKIES**  
We use cookies in connection with your use of the Mines’ website. A cookie is a small data file that is placed on your device when you visit a website. Cookies are widely used in order to make websites work or to work more efficiently, as well as to provide reporting information. A cookie may have unique identifiers and reside, among other places, on your device, in emails we send to you, and on our website. It is against Mines policy to share this information with external third parties and cookies created by Mines web pages cannot be read by a third party. 

Cookies may be set by parties other than Mines. These third-party cookies may originate from other websites for which www.mines.edu has implemented plug- ins. You are responsible for determining the cookie policy of any of these third- parties by visiting the privacy policy pages of these sites directly.

Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them. You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser. If you do choose to block cookies with your browser, some web sites, including Mines, may no longer work for you. For details on how to prevent your browser from accepting cookies, or how to disable cookies, follow your browser instructions.

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT**  
Mines may update this Privacy Statement at any time. When we do, we will revise the date at the bottom of this page and we will notify you here, by means of a notice on the Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to check this page frequently for any changes. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this Privacy Statement periodically.

**CONTACT US**  
There are various mechanisms for contacting us with comments, questions, or concerns. **[Contact Us](https://www.mines.edu/privacy/contact-us/)**.

Last Updated: January 25, 2019
